# Marina Limeira

## http://marinalimeira.com

Rua do Paraíso, 720 - Paraíso | São Paulo, 04103-001 +55 (82) 99613-3176 | marinaflessa@gmail.com

### 25th October 2017

# Personal summary

Hello! I was born in Palmeira dos Índios/AL. I moved to Maceió/AL in 2015 to go to college. Since I knew how to program (just in Pascal and Java by that time), I get my first "job" on my first month at college. After that, I get a intership and right after I get my first remote job at an american startup. I'm living in São Paulo since July. My current interests are about learn and improve my skills of Funcional Programming (unfortunately, I never had a 'production' experience with this) and architecture stuff, mainly on how we can develop huge platforms that can comunicate asyncronously stable and without losing data. I have experience working with HTML-CSS-JS things, despite I'm not focusing on that right now, I'm always reading articles and improving this skills too:)

#### Education

- Undergraduate (2017-now) Computer Science, Pontifical University Catholic of São Paulo
- Undergraduate (2015-2017) Computer Science, Federal University of Alagoas -Maceió
- Techinan (2011-2014) Computing, Federal Institute of Alagoas Palmeira dos Índios

# **Employment**

• jan/2017 - now: Systems Analyst, Bionexo

I'm helping to create their new platform, using Ruby on Rails and React. My biggest challenge is to develop on top of many platforms that they have, since many things are asynchronous (with the help of AWS SNS/SQS and Sidekiq) and also I'm working with (not an expert, I just had a brief contact) with Redis, ElasticSearch.

• nov/2016 - now: Freelancer Web Developer, Testr - remote

At Testr I'm a fullstack developer. My current tools are Ruby on Rails, jQuery and PostgreSQL as database.

- out/2016 dez/2016: Software Developer, CodeMiner42 remote
  - Worked in a project with Django and another using React.
- jun/2016: Intern, Bionexo São Paulo/SP

I had an brief experience at Bionexo during my college vocation of 2016. Since I was strongly working with testing tools by that time, I focused on working with others QAs to improve their testing automation flow.

dez/2015 - set/2016: Quality Assurance Developer, Tidy - Costa Mesa/CA - remote

My goal at Tidy was to develop an automated build that checks if the platform is working. My automation tools included Cucuber, Selenium, Docker and Ruby.

• may/2015 - dez/2015: Intern, RogaLabs - Maceió/AL

I had at Roga Labs my first contact with Ruby on Rails. My daily routine used to include Git Flow along with TDD and BDD.

### **Talks**

- 2017: Create your own reality with A-frame @ W3C Web.br 24th October 2017
- 2017: Create your own reality with A-frame @ DevFestNE 22th October 2017
- 2017: Software Quality: wat? @ Front in BH 23th September
- 2017: Nodebots: robôs com JS @ Flisol Maceió 08th April
- 2017: HTML & CSS Codelab (IWD '17) @ Rather Coworking 11th March
- 2017: JavaScript Funcional @ Bionexo 26th January
- 2016: JavaScript Funcional [pt-BR] @ Front in Aracaju 03rd December
- 2016: Nodebots: robôs com JS @ PotiCon 19th November
- 2016: Qualidade de Software: como e porquê? [pt-BR] @ DevFestNE 22th October
- 2016: Nodebots: robôs com JS [pt-BR] @ W3C Web.br 14th October
- 2016: Git Workshop [pt-BR] @ UFAL 7th July
- 2016: WoMakersCode Codelab [pt-BR] @ Senac 19th March
- 2015: Customizando a sua web com Add-ons [pt-BR] @ JSday Recife 12th December
- 2015: Ruby [pt-BR] @ Cesmac Info2016 18th and 19th November
- 2015: FirefoxOS [pt-BR] @ JSday Maceió 12th September

### Experience with volunteer jobs

- 2017: Coach at Rails Girls São Paulo
- 2016: Organizer of Rails Girls Maceió
- 2016: Organizer and instructor at WoMakersCode Marathon workshop to teach HTML/CSS to woman
- 2015: Organizer of Rails Girls Maceió
- 2015-now: Volunteer at Mozilla, main focused on teaching the web and translating articles to pt-BR